DOMINIC DUGGAN

DEVELOPER & GAME DESIGNER

SUMMARY

A dedicated first-year Immersive Technologies student at the University of Winchester with a strong foundation in game development, 3D modelling, and programming. Experienced in using Unity, C#, and Blender to create engaging and innovative projects. Eager to apply skills and knowledge to real-world challenges in a professional setting.

EXPERIENCE

RARA GAMES - VOLUNTEER DEVELOPER

Nov 2024 - Present

Developed the Save/Load system for **Tomebound**. I worked as part of a medium-sized team, used industry standard tools and methodology to collaborate as a team, and learned a lot in the process. Additionally, I wrote documentation for the systems I created, and helped the team integrate them into the main game. I developed skills in **time management**, **Unity**, **C#**, and **collaboration**.

INDEPENDENT GAME DEVELOPER

June 2023 - Present

Focused on creating innovative and engaging games using Unity and C#. My projects, although small in scope, reflect my **dedication to learning** and **applying new skills**. The role requires me to be the **lead developer**, and to excel in **time management** by planning project timelines and ensuring timely reaching of milestones.

I also work as the **lead game designer** and am proficient in **3D modelling** and texturing using industry-standard techniques and workflows. This role allows me to explore creative and unique game mechanics and approach the projects from both a designer's viewpoint and that of a programmer.

VOLUNTEER TECHNICAL SUPPORT

Feb 2019 - Sept 2022

I provided **technical assistance** to classmates and teachers, resolving issues with software, hardware, and other IT-related problems. This experience expanded my **problem-solving** skills and allowed to improve my **communication** and client-rapport, while working **collaboratively** with peers and educators

CONTACT

ddominic778@gmail.com +44 7305688881 github.com/domdgn Winchester, UK

ABOUT ME

I have a passion for game development and new technologies. I love to be immersed in virtual reality, and experience new and innovative methods for user-interaction. I am strongly motivated to excel in this field, to live out a life-long dream.

I always have fun developing and iterating on new ideas, and I love to learn from past mistakes.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WINCHESTER

BSc (Hons) Immersive Technologies

PRIESTLEY COLLEGE

A Level Physics, Biology, Chemistry

PADGATE ACADEMY

9 GCSEs - Grade 7 and above

SKILLS & ATTRIBUTES

- Software/Game Development C#, HTML, CSS, JS, Python
- 3D Modelling Blender, Fusion 360
- Creative Design Concept Art, Level Design, Texturing
- **Problem-Solving** I love to solve new challenges

PROJECTS

GROUP GAME PROJECT

Nov - Dec 2024

I worked as one of the **developers** in a 6-week game project for my university course. We were tasked with **conceptualising**, **designing**, and **developing** a game that is suitable for a PEGI 7 rating or lower. I developed core features such as the character controller, enemy AI, and took the role as **lead** when applicable.

STYLISED 3D DIORAMA ENVIRONMENT

Sept - Dec 2024

I **designed** and **3D modelled** a stylised diorama in **Blender**, showcasing a unique game environment with procedural shading and custom models.

I integrated the diorama into **Unity**, adding interactive elements to develop a 3D environment with a sense of life and story to it.

TOP-DOWN 3D SHOOTER

Oct 2024

I developed a top-down shooter game with infinitely generated terrain, continuous enemy spawning, and a **dynamic** weapon and shop system.

I utilized **C# scripting** in **Unity** to create responsive controls and engaging gameplay mechanics.

I **arranged playtests** and iterated on the design and function of the game to ensure it was engaging and fun to play.

CONTACT

ddominic778@gmail.com +44 7305688881 github.com/domdgn Winchester, UK

ASPIRATIONS

I aspire to work in an industryleading work environment, working to solve new and interesting problems and challenges.

REFERENCES

References available upon request.